# 大家好 家裡的剩飯剩菜太多啦 那小狗都吃不完
Hi everyone! We have far too much leftover at home. Those doggies just can't finish it.
# 去兄弟家搞條豬來
I'm gonna fetch a pig from my buddy's place.
# 用豬來吃 合理利用 那就不會沒 沒有那個浪
I use a pig. It's called reasonable utilisation. Then it won't be, not so, there won't be so, I mean...
# 不會浪費啦 就沒有那麼多那個剩飯剩菜扔出去
We won't be wasting so much food. We won't need to throw away so much, you know, so much leftover.
# 小豬幾乎甚麼都可以吃的掉
Piggies eat almost everything.
# 你看 香蕉 好多哇
Look! Bananas. A lot!
# 下面還有池塘哦
There's also a pond down there.
# 兄弟家豬場在上面一點
My buddy's pig farm is just a bit up there.
# 那條鵝我抓一下看抓不抓很到 好大啊
That goose, let me see if I can catch it. It's huge!
# 全啄人的這個雞
It pecks, this chicken.
# 大公雞
A big rooster
# 你看 我們養的那鵝就前面那個小的一樣那麼大
Look! Our geese are only as big as the small one in the front,
# 那麼大一點點哦
or a tiny little bit larger.
# 你看 這個鵝好大啊 大了一兩倍
Look! This goose is really big. It's double or even triple in size.
# 你看
Look!
# 那麼大
It's so big!
# 豬就在這裡面 我們進去看一下
The pigs are here inside. Let's get in and have a look.
# 你看
Look!
# 一堆喲 小豬崽
A bunch of them, piglets
# 比較小的這些
These are a bit smaller.
# 你看 這就是兄弟養的
Look! These are my buddy's,
# 香豬
Huanjian pigs.
# 嘴巴好像尖 尖了一些
Their mouths seem to be a bit, a bit pointed.
# 你看 這小豬好可愛喲
Look! These piglets are really cute.
# 它一
In one,
# 它一窩就生了十來條
there's a dozen of piglets in a single litter.
# 這兩條都是母的
Both of them are sow.
# 你看 這個豬欄都是就地取材 全部是用那個小木頭
Look! This pigsty is built with local and natural resources. These are all small logs.
# 一根一根釘起來的
They were nailed one by one.
# 把紥實的哦
It's really firm, you know.
# 好啦 終於把它抓 抓回來啦
Alright! Finally we've, we've got it.
# 我它拉回我們家去
We're gonna take it back to our site.
# 呃 順便帶一隻雞回去
Eh, why don't we take a chicken with us?
# 你看 這些都是放養雞來的 很好吃的哦
Look! These are all free range chickens. They taste really good, you know.
# 拿抄網來抄 抄一個來
Let me get a catching net, and catch one.
# 有沒抓到
Got it?
# 你看 這是老閹雞來的哦
Look! This is an old capon.
# 這個雞閹過了的
It has been castrated.
# 肉質很好吃的
The texture of the meat is really good.
# 沒蛋
No balls
# 可以 好啦 我們先回去
Okay, alright! Let's go back first.
# 一百三十
A hundred and thirty...
# 三十二
thirty two
# 一百三十
A hundred and thirty
# 胡韦汝
Hu Weiru!
# 你看 這頭豬
Have a look at this pig!
# 太胖啦 身上的肥膘都出來啦
It's too fat. Its whole body is covered with fat.
# 我先放到這個 這個豬欄裡面餓它三天三夜
I'll first put it in the, in the pigsty and starve it for three whole days and nights.
# 然後再來餵 餵朲西給它吃 它就會吃啦
And then I'll feed it, feed it something. It will be eating then.
# 你看 生無可戀一樣
Look! It seems that it has lost all its meanings of life.
# 可以 我又不會對你怎麼啦
Fine! I'm not doing any harm to you.
# 剛好把它移過這裡來
Right now we can move it to this side.
# 出去出去 你自由啦
Get out, get out! You're free now!
# 這裡
Here,
# 這很好玩的哦 你不出來
there's so much fun here, you now. Why aren't you coming out?
# 拍不屁股 拍你屁股 不出來
Spank you, I spank you. You're not coming out.
# 這個豬受驚嚇啦
This pig, is traumatised.
# 很怕人
It's very scared of people.
# 一直 以為 以為馬上就要吃它啦
It keeps thinking, thinking that we might eat it immediately.
# 不理我
No response
# 你看 它現在一動不動的
Look! It's now like a statue.
# 先餓它三天三夜 去一下它身上的油脂
Let's first starve it for three whole days and nights, to get rid some of the oil and fat on its body.
# 然後再想辦法 看一下怎麼
And then let's see, how we can,
# 怎麼煮它
how we can cook it.
# 紅燒還是清蒸 還是烤
Would it be stew, or steam, or grill?
# 理都不理人
It ignores me completely.
# 肯定害怕受了驚嚇 沒事
It must be scared. It's traumatised. No worries.
# 明天就好啦
It will be alright tomorrow.
# 你看 這還有個南瓜哦
Look! Here are also some pumpkins.
# 以前是 以前那 那批豬種的
They were there, they were planted by our pre, previous batch of pigs.
# 這裡還有一個
Here's one more.
# 來 拿點南瓜給你吃
C'mon! Here are some pumpkins for you!
# 這個南瓜
These are pumpkins.
# 看它吃不吃 哎呀
Let's see if it's eating. Aya!
# 一動不動
It's like a statue.
# 它又想吃又害怕
It wants to eat but it's scared.
# 沒事
No worries!
# 過段時間就好啦
It will be alright after some time.
# 不管它啦
Leave it alone.
# 過兩天再來看它
I'll come again in a couple of days.
# 餓不死它 它那麼胖
It can survive. It's so fat.
# 豬已經安頓好啦
So now the pig is settled down.
# 就安排這隻鴨
It's time for the duck.
# 這隻不是鴨 這是雞
It's not a duck. It's a chicken.
# 把刀磿鋒利一點
Let me sharpen the knife. Make it a bit sharper.
# 你看 這隻雞已經殺好啦
Look! This chicken is now ready.
# 又大又肥 你看
It's big and fat. Look!
# 它肉很結實哦 好重啊 這隻雞
Its meat is really firm. It's so heavy, this chicken.
# 我先把它砍碎先
Let me chop it up first.
# 我把這雞
I'm gonna chop,
# 翅肪 先抇它砍下來
chop the chicken wings first.
# 要搞大塊一點
I'll chop it up in larger pieces.
# 隨便吃
Feel free to take it.
# 我都還沒吃
Don't try to eat before me!
# 雞屁股你們吃
The chicken butt is yours.
# 你看這個肉 它還會動的 一跳一跳 夠新鮮
Have a look at the meat! It's still moving, trembling. That means it's fresh.
# 拍點生薑下去
I smash some ginger.
# 放點生薑下去 再搞點香菇 這香菇要洗一下
Put some ginger, and also some shiitake mushrooms. The mushrooms need to be washed first.
# 這香菇洗好啦 直接倒進去
So the mushroom have been washed. I just pour them in right away.
# 再加點山泉水
Then put some spring water.
# 這個 多加點水
Well, a bit more water
# 湯就多一點
Then we can have more soup.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 哇 這個
Wa! This,
# 這個火夠猛
this fire is really strong.
# 這狗還戴了個眼鏡
This dog is wearing eyeglasses.
# 我去看一下那兩頭羊 剛剛下來啦 看到我它又跑
Let me go and have a look at the two goats. They have just come down. But they ran away once they saw me.
# 我搞又個樹叉 樹叉給它 給它吃
I'm taking a branch, a branch for them, to feed them.
# 跑哪裡去啦
Where are they?
# 你看這些羊
Have a look at these goats!
# 給它吃那樹上的嫩葉子哦 草它都不怎麼喜歡吃
I'm giving them the young leaves on the tree. They don't really like grass.
# 好多象草都 沒有利用起來
I have a lot of elephant grass here, but no use.
# 搞頭牛來
I'm gonna fetch a cow.
# 四大家禽
Four types of major livestock
# 四大家禽都齊啦 豬 雞鴨鵝牛羊
We'll then have all four types of major livestock, pigs, chickens, ducks, geese, cattle and goats.
# 還有兔子也有
And we have bunnies too.
# 好膽小現在這個羊
This goat is now a coward.
# 我把鏈子全部解掉啦 它們自由自在在這生活著
I've taken away all the leashes. So they can enjoy the free and worrieless life here.
# 很幸福哦它們
That's exactly what life should be.
# 每天都吃的飽飽的
They have more than enough to eat every day.
# 很多粉絲說這個羊 這毎羊像瓜子一樣
A lot of fans say that this goat, this goat looks like a pumpkin seed.
# 它頭羊頭是有點像哦
Yes, its head looks a bit like a pumpkin seed.
# 一白一黑的 瓜子臉
Black and white, pumpkin seed face.
# 瓜子臉就這樣子的
That's what pumpkin seed face means.
# 對我們愛理不理 它們吃它們的
They are completely indifferent to us. They eat their own food.
# 我們
And we,
# 我們拍我們的
we film our own video.
# 不知道甚麼時候能下小羊
I wonder when they are gonna give birth to babies.
# 你看 我一 我一站起來它們就走
Look! Once I, once I stand up, they run away immediately.
# 這就是你們的遊樂場 想去哪裡就去哪裡
This is your playground. You can go wherever you like.
# 來來來 這個好吃的
Come here, come here! This is tasty.
# 這個才好吃 我去看一下那個豬
This one tastes much better. I'm gonna have a look at the pig.
# 你看這隻豬
Have a look at the pig!
# 一動不動 吃也不吃喝也不喝的
It's like a statue. It's not eating, nor drinking.
# 它不來 不來拉倒
It's not coming. Forget it then.
# 它在那裡睡大覺吧 多睡幾天
Let it have a good sleep there, sleep for a few more days.
# 這個豬的鼻子
The nose of this pig,
# 好像小一點 又尖
seems to be a bit smaller, and pointed.
# 以前我那個是又圓
The noses of our previous pigs were, round and,
# 圓圓的 而且比較大
they were round, and, and were larger.
# 像那個山上的野豬一樣
It's like a wild boar in the mountain.
# 理一下我誒 理都不理我
Give me some response. Why aren't you giving me any response at all?
# 站起來 站起來給我看一下你的身材
Stand up! Stand up and show me your physique!
# 看你身材好不好 快點
Let me see if you have a good body.
# 這石頭 扔給你吃的
These are rocks. You can eat them.
# 我是叫你站起來 肚子那麼大
I ask you to stand up! You have such a big belly.
# 哎呀 石頭它也吃啊
Aya! It's really eating rocks.
# 很厲害哦 它那牙齒哦
They're so powerful, its teeth.
# 肚子那麼大 是不是懷孕了
You have such a big belly. Are you pregnant?
# 你是一頭公豬 而且還被閹了的
You're a boar. What's more, you're castrated.
# 可能閹 閹過之後那個肉比較好吃 所以就
Perhaps the texture of the pork from a cas, castrated pig is better. So I,
# 叫兄弟提前就把它閹了
I asked my buddy to have it castrated beforehand.
# 不理人的這隻豬
It's not giving any response, this pig.
# 可能比較陌生
Perhaps it's not familiar to this place.
# 過段時間來
A bit more time,
# 過段時間來它就不陌生了
it will more familiar to this place after a bit more time.
# 還有兩隻鴨一個鵝
There are still two ducks and one goose.
# 等著它們下蛋
I'm waiting for their eggs.
# 再不下蛋的話
And if they're still not laying eggs,
# 就把它宰了
I'll kill them.
# 天天在偷看我 那隻瓜子臉
It's peeping me every day, that pumpkin seed face.
# 一看到我來了就跑
It runs away once it sees me.
# 哎呀 好香啊 你看
Aya! It smells so good! Look!
# 湯都滿起來啦 現在要 小火 小火慢燉
It's now full of soup. Now low heat, cook it on low heat.
# 燉到吃飯的時候就可以直接吃了
Then we can eat it right away at meal time.
# 我先把其他菜先煮了先
Let me cook other dishes first.
# 留一點火給它
I leave a little bit fire here.
# 開吃開吃 我先吃一下
Meal time, meal time! Let me be the first one.
# 香
Nice!
# 你看這香菇
Have a look at the mushrooms here!
# 婀娜多姿的身材
It looks so flirtatious.
# 讓我找個雞朖來嘗一下
Let me find a chicken leg and have a try.
# 哇 這個雞眼夠大啦
Wa! This chicken leg is really big!
# 這個雞腿
This chicken leg,
# 看上去都有食慾
it looks so appetising.
# 要拿著吃 雞腿要食著吃才好吃
I gotta hold it by hands. That's the only correct way to enjoy a chicken leg.
# 有點
It's a bit,
# 有點燙
a bit hot.
# 看上去是不是很有食慾
Does it look appetising?
# 兄弟家的雞就是不一樣
Buddy's chicken always makes a difference.
# 養了差不多快一年啦 這隻雞
He has been raising it for almost a year, this chicken.
# 被我抓回來
And now I've caught it.
# 它這隻雞不是公的 也不是母的哦
This chicken is neither a rooster, nor a hen, you know,
# 是閹的
but a capon.
# 好燙
It's hot!
# 雞腿也那麼大
It's just a chicken leg and it's so big.
# 沒那麼快
Not so soon
# 去媽媽那裡去 去 不要拿出來
Go to your mother, go! Don't take it out!
# 去
Go!
# 你看 這香菇
Look! This mushroom...
# 好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 等下叫他們一起過來吃 那麼大鍋
I'll ask them to come here and enjoy it together. It's such a big wok.